Now how do we practice for Tribal belly dancing?
Hi, I'm Johanna Krynytzky with Hip Expressions Belly Dance Studio.
Now, let's talk about practice sessions for Tribal belly dance.
Now there's different types of tribal style belly dancing.
Alright, you have Improvisational Tribal style which developed out of San Francisco in the 1980s and that's where you dance with a group working on cues and improvisations.
In that case, what you needed to do to practice is to practice with your group.
There are certain moves that you need to practice over and over and over again until you have them precisely correct.
Now, there's also Tribal Fusion styles of belly dance which developed a little bit later, and there's many, many different movements for that.
So, depending on what you're practicing, everything comes back to having your basic isolations.
So, you want to practice in front of a mirror with your partners, or if you're doing solo, by yourself, making sure your feet are together, under your hips, your knees are bent.
Your belly buttons pulled in.
Your chest is lifted.
Your shoulders are back and down.
Arms out away from the body.
And now, again the arm position is going to vary.
If you're doing more Tribal Fusion, or if you're doing more Improvisational Tribal Style.
So, it depends on where your arms are supposed to go, but ultimately, you want your isolations to remain nice and precise.
So, that you get nice clean movements out of your dancing.
I'm Johanna Krynytzky from Hip Expressions Belly Dance Studio helping you to practice your Tribal belly dance.